Guide to the Sybil Huntington May Papers, 1898-1976 (bulk 1910-1919)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Sybil Huntington May Papers
1898-1976
1910-1919
May, Sybil Huntington
2 cubic feet (2 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Materials related to May’s life as a student at Vassar and during the years immediately after her graduation. There is also correspondence related to Leo Huberman, co-founder of the Monthly Review.
Biographical Note
Educator Sybil Huntington May taught at the progressive City and Country School in New York City for 24 years before becoming a charter staff member of the Monthly Review. May was born in 1893 in New York City, the daughter of Charles and Carder Collins May. She attended the Charlton School, before entering Vassar in 1910. Her post-Vassar education included the New York School of Philanthropy (1914-1915) and Teachers College of Columbia University where she earned an M.A. in 1917. Her early career in education included teaching English at Miss Pond’s School in Newark, New Jersey (1917-1918), English and History at Miss Chapin’s School in New York City (1918-1922, 1923-1926) and the sixth grade at Francis Parker School in Chicago(1922-1923). She taught from 1926 until 1950 at the City and Country School in New York City. Upon her retirement, she began working with the Monthly Review, serving as the a proofreader and Executive Secretary of Monthly Review Associates, which raised funds for the non-profit publication. With the magazine's co-founder Leo Huberman, she co-wrote the ABC of Socialism (New York: Monthly Review, 1953), which was translated into Spanish, Swedish, Telugu, and Finnish. She died October 3, 1978.
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains correspondence and photographs documenting the lives of May, her family, and friends, many of whom also attended Vassar College. Of special note are portrayals of family life in letters to May while she was at Vassar and observations by young socially conscious Vassar alumnae.
Correspondence from the late 1960’s includes material related to Leo Huberman, co-founder of the Monthly Review.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Subject Headings
Names:
Huberman, Leo, 1903-1968
Organizations:
Vassar College--Alumni and alumnae; Vassar College--Students
VCL Categories
Vassar College
Encoding Information
Encoded by Jessica Kemm, September 2009.
Acquisition Information
Correspondence from 1915-1918 was donated by Edward Huberman in 1990 and is included in Series 2.
Series List
- Series I. Biographical Information
- Series II. Letters to Sybil H. May
- Series III. Letters From Sybil H. May
- Series IV. Photographs
Container List
- Series I: Biographical Information
  - Biographical Information (Folder 1.1)
  - Sybil May estate information, donation to Vassar College (Folder 1.2)
  - Journal, 1920s? (Folder 1.3)
  - War Ration Books (Folder 1.4)
- Series II: Letters to Sybil H. May
  - Letters from family members, 1898 - 1922, n.d. (Folders 1.5 - 1.25)
  - Boody, Bertha (Folder 1.26)
  - Brainerd, Bertha/Cephas (Folder 1.27)
  - Brant, Lilian (Folder 1.28)
  - Brinsmade, Dorothy (Folder 1.29)
  - Chapin, Maria B. (Folder 1.30)
  - Colcord, J.C. (Folder 1.31)
  - Deming, Dorothy (VC 1914) (Folder 1.32)
  - Dorothy ? (Folder 1.33)
  - Dubois, Helen (Folder 1.34)
  - Fowler, Katherine (Folder 1.35)
  - Fuller, Carding (Folder 1.36)
  - Geuder, Agnes (Folder 1.37)
  - Gleason, Josephine [Jo] (VC 1914), ca. 1916-1919 (Folders 1.38 - 1.43)
  - Green, Annie L. (VC 1914) (Folder 1.44)
  - Griff, Helen (Folder 1.45)
  - Howe, Susana (Folder 1.46)
  - Jamieson, Edith (VC 1914) (Folder 1.47)
  - Jeanette? (Folder 1.48)
  - Katherine? (Folder 1.49)
  - Kelley, Margaret [Mardie] (Folders 1.50 - 1.51)
  - Lee? (Folder 2.1)
  - McDaniels, Harriet (Folder 2.2)
  - Mallon, Mary (VC 1915) (Folder 2.3)
  - Marguerita (Folder 2.4)
  - Mary? (Folder 2.5)
  - Noble, Evelyn (Folder 2.6)
  - Rufus? (Folder 2.7)
  - Rilling, Ruth (VC 1914) (Folder 2.8)
  - Roberts, Willa [Billie] (VC 1914) (Folder 2.9)
  - Stanley, Louise (VC 1914) (Folder 2.10)
  - Taylor, Margaret (VC ex 1915) (Folder 2.11)
  - Underhill, Elsie (Folder 2.12)
  - Underhill, Gertrude (Folder 2.13)
  - Vanneman, Aimeé (VC 1914) (Folder 2.14)
  - Willard, Marion [Marnie] (VC 1914) (Folder 2.15)
  - Miscellaneous, Jan 1912 - Sep 1914 (Folder 2.16)
  - Letters from non-family members, 1910 - 1976, n.d. (Folders 2.17 - 2.42)
  - Letters from others to others, Dec 1911- Feb 1912, Oct 1921 (Folder 2.43)
  - Letters acquired from Edward Huberman, 1914-1918 (Folders 2.51 - 2.55)
- Series III: Letters from Sybil H. May
  - Letters to her parents, 1923 (Folders 2.44 - 2.45)
  - Letters to her mother, 1911, 1919, 1923, n.d. (Folders 2.46 - 2.48)
- Series IV: Photographs
  - Photographs (Folders 2.49 - 2.50)